Jethro Hazelhurst

77 Scottby Road Carlisle, UK Mobile: 0800.00.1066

Email: j.hazelhurst1994@gmail.com Visit: jethrohazelhurst.github.com

Web Developer and Frontend Engineer

I love getting into the nuts and bolts of a project. I am highly self motivated, with nearly 2 years of experience designing intuitive web applications. I work with a view to maintainability and have an obsession with the details that make or break a successful project.

Skills

Programming and Markup Languages

PHP, JavaScript (ES6), HTML5, CSS3, MySQL, JSON

Tools and Libraries

jQuery, SCSS, Bower, GIT, Github, Composer, Codelgniter

Protocols and Patterns

 $\hbox{HTTP, MVC/MV$^*, SOLID, AJAX, Websockets, Responsive Design}$

Soft Skills

Excellent Communication, Problem Solver, Analytical, Focused,

Friendly, Eager to learn

Spoken Languages

English (Native), French (Fluent)

Experience

TwoCan English

2016 - Present

TwoCan English is a platform that provides English language training to students around the world across multiple time zones. I hand coded TwoCan English (https://twocan.co) from scratch and it has taught me just what it takes to deliver a complete online software suit that people rely on every day.

Smart-Drones

2013 - 2015

I designed, prototyped and tested UAV drone hardware as well as designed and marketed the website. My work at Smart-Drones taught me the importance of brand development and marketing.

Metalbot 3D Metal Printing

2013 - 2015

An initiative that I kick-started. Our goal? To develop the worlds first open source 3D metal printer. I brought together a community of passionate hardware hackers which taught me the value of a supportive community.

Education

FCC Frontend Certification CodeCademy MITx Circuits & Electronics

Interests

Robotics
Open Source Electronics and Hardware 3D Printing
Radio Control
Web Development Community
Music Composition
Classical Piano (11 Years!)